[wind howling]
[baby crying]
[YAMAHA] There's another child
inside you!
-It's truly happening... twins!
-[Nagisa grunting]
You've nearly made it to dawn!
You must resist
the urge to push!
Resist? You know you're asking
the impossible, Granny!
[YAMAHA]
That doesn't matter!
[Nagisa groaning]
Even if it's impossible,
she must.
If she does this,
her children will be the ones
to place the Daemons
under their command!
♪
[babies crying]
[babies continue crying]
[Mine grunts softly]
[MINE] The children who sunder
night and day
have been born to us.
♪
DAEMONS OF THE SHADOW REALM
16 YEARS LATER
[birds calling]
[thuds]
[footsteps]
[plane flying overhead]
[YURU] Perfect trails
of dragon wind.
EPISODE 1
"ASA AND YURU"
[Danji groans]
[DANJI] Hm? [chuckles]
Hey, Yuru, don't tell me.
Did you go hunting
by yourself again?
[YURU] Hey, Danji,
just got back.
[DANJI] You know
I would've gone with
-if you would've asked!
-Sorry.
What if something happened
in the mountains
while you were
by yourself, huh?
What would you have done?
[YURU] It's fine, really.
I trust the Left and the Right
to protect me.
[Danji laughs] Wow!
You nabbed yourself a pheasant?
That must've been hard!
[YURU] Not really.
We're havin' roast pheasant
tonight! [chuckles]
-[YURU] Stewed.
-[DANJI] No way.
Roast pheasant smells
and tastes way better.
[YURU] Stew will make you
feel full longer.
[DANJI] Ah, who cares?
Hey, Yuru, welcome back.
Get ready.
We're in for bad weather
tonight.
[sighs] That's fine by me
as long as it means rain.
Do you want some help later?
Sure! Thanks, kid!
♪
[BOY] Huh? Oh! [chuckles]
[BOY] Hey!
[man chuckles]
[Kyoka grunting]
[Kyoka sighs]
[YURU] Granny Yamaha, I'm back.
You look well, Yuru.
Danji, your timing
couldn't be better!
[Danji exclaims] But Mom!
Stop your whining!
[DANJI] Look at that. Gotta go!
Come back!
Why can't you be
more diligent like Yuru?
Granny, how's Asa?
Good. That sister of yours
has been working
since you left for the hunt.
[YURU] Asa...
How are you?
Big brother, welcome back home!
[Yuru chuckles]
♪
[YURU] I caught
a pheasant today.
That's so impressive!
It's really not.
I was hoping to catch a boar
or a deer instead.
It's been so dry all year.
I'm worried the crops might die.
If that happens, food will be
scarce for the winter.
I need to hunt more,
then preserve it with salt,
or make jerky.
[ASA] If the harvest
does wind up that bad,
will the adults have
to go down the mountain
to find work?
It's possible.
[ASA] Will you be leaving
to join them?
Not a chance!
Look, why do you think I've been
putting in so much time
to get better at hunting?
I'd do anything to keep
from going down the mountain,
so I'll just make myself
too valuable to send away.
You promise you're not gonna
leave me alone?
You won't abandon us
the same way our parents did?
You do not need to worry, Asa.
I swear I'll protect you
for as long as I live.
I am never going to leave
this village!
Not while you're here!
The two of us
will stick together!
[ASA)] Huh?
[chuckles] Always!
-[Yuru chuckles]
-[KYOKA] Yuru.
What's wrong?
[KYOKA] Mm...
Nothing. Dera's here.
♪
[MAN] This is some good steel.
[DERA] These are from the guys
who just left.
[MAN]
Thanks for always doing this.
How is it down there, anyway?
There's been a nasty illness
going around.
Our luck. Yeah?
Hear that? Means I'll be buying
medicinal herbs at a premium!
I'll trade these for some salt.
Got any seeds for veggies
that don't need much rain?
[DERA] But of course.
Excuse me,
my girl's turning seven soon.
[DERA] Time sure flies!
I'll bring a shaman with me
on my next trip!
[BOTH] Mm... [chuckling]
My headaches
have been getting worse.
Your usual painkillers?
[indistinct chatter]
-[DERA] On it!
-[YURU] Uh?
Dera!
Hey, Yuru! How ya been?
Anything
you're lookin' for today?
Well, there's nothing
that I need. Uh...
"My sister on the other hand.
I'll take anything you've got!"
Right?
-[YURU] Hmm.
-[indistinct chatter]
It's perfect.
[DERA] What? You've got
pheasant feathers?
Look at you!
Those sell for a fortune!
[DANJI] He's so lucky.
I wish I could leave
the village for a day.
[YURU] What, do you think
it's nice? Out there?
Consider all the people
who left us.
We rarely see them come back
to this boring place.
It must be way better
than being a peasant. Like me!
I'm not so sure.
I wouldn't mind living
in this village my whole life.
[DANJI] Easy for you to say.
You've got a cute little sister
to keep you company.
Why don't you just take her
and get out of this life?
I'll be happy to come along,
if that'd make you feel safer.
I can't have you hanging
around Asa. You'd corrupt her.
[exclaims] What'd you say?
Asa has an important job here!
You got it?
Great! But if no one
can actually see her,
how do we know
she's not imaginary?
Only a select few may visit her.
Aren't I "select" enough,
big brother?
Sorry, but an oaf like you will
probably never get to meet her.
[Danji grunts]
Those are fightin' words!
[YURU] Fine, you can
see her if you win!
[DANJI] Wait, no, no, no,
no, no, no, no, no!
-[plane flying overhead]
-[DANJI] Uh?
What's that sound?
I'm pretty sure
it's just another dragon.
-Look there.
-Uh?
[YURU] More trails
of dragon wind.
[helicopter whirring]
That roar is unusual.
This one sounds almost rhythmic.
I've heard some like it
a few times before,
when I was hunting deep
in the mountains.
It's pretty loud, though, right?
Maybe it's close.
Hey, man, have you ever
seen a dragon?
Never, no.
♪
What's that thing?
[both gasp]
[helicopter whirring]
[horse neighs]
-[both exclaim]
-[BOY] Hey!
[all gasp]
[muffled grunting]
[Dera gasping]
[gunshots in distance]
Hey! So, Granny Yamaha,
do you know
what's going on here?
It's the barrier.
They managed
to destroy it somehow.
How'd they do that?
I don't know.
But they're probably trying
-to abduct Yuru.
-Huh?
We have to hide him
somewhere safe right now!
-Bring him straight away to me!
-Right!
[MAN 1] Where is he?
[MAN 2] Most likely
in the fields below! Hurry!
[DANJI] What's this?
What happened here?
[Danji breathes shakily]
They're all dead.
I don't understand.
-[YURU] Danji, stay close.
-[Danji grunts]
Please, Mom.
Please still be alive!
[Danji panting]
[Combatant 1 gasps]
That's the boy!
[COMBATANT 2]
Stand down.
[shrieks] What's that?
Something flew by super-fast!
I don't know, but I don't think
you wanna get hit by one.
[combatants grunting]
[Danji panting]
Looks like those dragons
made it over the outer wall!
[YURU] I doubt
we could fight them.
Can you even call them dragons?
[Danji panting]
Well, my mom's probably
around the keep,
same place as usual.
And I'm guessing you're
also headed there
to find Asa? Huh?
[YURU] Give me a hand.
[Danji grunts] With what?
-[YURU] Just trust me.
-Hm?
[Danji grunts]
Whoa, what is this?
[YURU] A shortcut to the keep.
That was here? All this time?
I had no clue!
Told you.
The Left and Right
will protect us.
[ladder creaking]
Asa, stay safe.
[grunts] Hey, Yuru!
So how's it hangin', guys?
Gobble.
-[grunts]
-[villagers gasping]
-Gobble.
-[grunts]
-Gobbly-gob.
-[men grunting]
Gobble, gobble.
You too.
[Azami whimpers]
Mommy!
It's fine, I don't bite kids!
[man whimpering]
Gobble.
[Azami screams]
What up? This is Gabby.
The outer and middle zones
have been mostly emptied out.
Send the ground force,
we're all clear here.
[helicopter whirring]
Hey, is anyone listening?
Oh, man, what a mess.
What to do about all this?
Can't believe they managed
to break the barrier.
Hey, hey. Hana?
We got a problem here.
Damn, even the signal's
getting through.
This is bad.
Can you see the smoke
from there?
Great.
Looks like we gotta change
the rendezvous point.
Yep.
I'm pretty sure...
Asa's here.
Oh, yeah?
So that's the way it's gonna be.
[breathes nervously]
[ASA] Disgusting.
[Asa gasps]
DAEMONS OF THE SHADOW REALM
[ASA] Disgusting.
[Asa gasps]
[gasps]
[Yuru gasps]
-[YURU] Asa!
-[ASA] Yes?
Your Asa is right here.
I've come to save you.
-[Yuru gasps softly]
-And after that...
[Asa exhales sharply]
...I'm gonna kill
everybody else.
[gasps] Hold on.
Whoever you are, you're lying.
You clearly aren't.
[voice trembles] And she's...
You're not my sister! Drop dead!
Get away from her!
[DERA] They disguised themselves
as mountain rescue choppers.
[gunshots]
[DERA] Gotta make sure
they can't follow me from above
while I'm making my escape.
Oh, man...
My, my...
Well, little red,
what big teeth you have!
[Gabriel growls]
Wow. You can see
my friends, mister?
[gunshots]
That enamel's hard as rocks!
I take it you're the one
who killed our ground forces.
Huh?
[grunts]
My bad. I was only trying
to break the arrow.
I'm still getting used to this.
[Asa grunts]
Dera, take Yuru and escape!
[Yuru gasps]
[YAMAHA]
Hide in the world below!
You mustn't let them find you!
[DERA] Aye, aye!
-[Kyoka grunts]
-Mom, are you all right?
-[footsteps running]
-[Danji gasps]
[DANJI] Yuru?
Yuru!
[Dera grunts]
Let's go.
We're headed down
the mountain. Huh?
What kind of madness
is all this?
Where did they come from?
What's happening to our village?
-Save your questions!
-[gunshots]
Damn it, we missed our chance.
And if those dentures come back,
the enemy will have us flanked.
-Asa.
-Huh?
I watched my sister
die back there. [cries]
No, wait, is she dead?
I thought I saw her move.
But I left Granny
in a room with her.
Who even was that woman?
She said she'd kill them all.
But none of the villagers
did anything to deserve it!
[gunshots]
There's no time for me
to explain right now.
[Yuru breathing shakily]
[DERA] Use them,
the Left and Right.
Huh? What do you mean?
It's a necklace.
Over there.
There's a hole in the flagstones
between the Left and Right.
Put it there.
Mmm... And what do you think
that's gonna do?
Look, I'm givin' you
a gift, kid!
Explain!
Just take it, already!
It's gotta be you! Go on!
What? Everyone's so crazy today!
I just want answers.
Is that asking too much?
The hole's plugged up
with a bunch of junk!
Dig it out!
[COMBATANT]
That's the boy we're after.
Capture him.
Everyone else can die.
You really should clean up
around here!
[gunshot]
I got it. So now what?
That hurt, Dera!
What was that about?
[combatants grunting]
[both scream]
What's going on?
♪
[Yuru gasps]
[Yuru grunts]
[screams] No!
[GABBY] How am I supposed
to get back home now?
Walking down this mountain
is gonna suck bad.
-[Gabriel grumbles]
-Yeah, yeah.
Quit your gnashing, you two.
[Gabriel grumbles]
Something big went that way.
Whose daemons are those?
Hope they're not as strong
as they seemed.
[Yuru grunts]
[Right laughs]
Whoa, what is this?
Our new master is but a child.
Should be easy to control,
huh, Left?
[Right laughs]
[LEFT] Young, old,
it matters not.
-[Yuru gasps]
-[LEFT] We obey our master
regardless, Right.
[DERA] Ghosts, spirits,
monsters, aberrations,
cryptids...
They have many names.
Hard for folks to know
what to call them
when the only thing
consistent about them
is they always come in pairs.
Yuru, these are your Daemons.
Daemons?
[♪ closing theme song playing]
[MINE] The Left and Right's
bases at the village exit
are directly above us.
Listen to me, Yuru.
Know that no matter what happens
in the future,
the Left and Right
are watching over you.
EPISODE 2
LEFT AND RIGHT